# CHRISTOPHER DENO

Fairfax, VA 22031 • (818) 671-8222 • christopherdenq@gmail.com cdenq.github.io • github.com/cdenq • linkedin.com/in/christopherdenq

#### **SUMMARY**

Early data scientist with **1.5 years professional** and **3 years academic** experience in data analytics, machine learning, and database engineering. Strong mathematical foundation to analytics and AI from coursework and fellowship. Art market background confers prioritization of **customer and product sense**; self-taught transition into data demonstrates **grit, initiative, and commitment**.

## **EDUCATION**

#### University of Pennsylvania | Philadelphia, PA

BA, Philosophy and Art History Undergraduate, Statistics (Wharton) Jan 2017 – May 2021

Aug 2015 - Jan 2017

Note: Transferred from Statistics to Philosophy half-way through undergraduate career

#### University of Illinois - Springfield | Springfield, IL

BA, Mathematical Sciences, minor in Legal Studies

Jan 2023 - Present

- Note: Taking courses part-time to gain rigorous mathematical understanding of AI models
- Courses: Linear Algebra, Mathematical Statistics, Probability, Statistical Methods, MV Calc, Discrete Math., Dif EQs

#### INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

#### **Data Scientist Apprentice**

(4 mos) Mar 2023 – Jun 2023

Adobe & General Assembly | Remote

- Received scholarship from Adobe to General Assembly's Data Science Apprenticeship Program
- Fast-tracked to data science position with Adobe after apprenticeship

# **Data Analyst Intern**

(3 mos) Jun 2022 – Aug 2022

PNC Financial Services Group | Brecksville, OH

- Utilized SQL for data queries, Tableau for dashboard visualization, and Python/machine learning for forecasting
- Succeeded in saving company \$375,000 and creating 8 data products used by 90+ members across 7 departments

#### **Data Analytics Assistant Instructor & Tutor**

(1 yr 3 mos) Sep 2021 – Nov 2022

2U – Trilogy Education Services & Wyzant.com | Atlanta, GA & Remote

- Managed and taught data analytics curriculum; teaching and tutoring over 300+ hours to 65 students
- Successfully performs code reviews, provides feedback on projects, and teaches CS concepts

#### **Leading Art Auction House Intern**

(3 mos) Jun 2020 – Aug 2020

Christie's Auctions & Private Sales | New York, NY

- Evaluated 12 artworks over 6+ reports and collection documentation; attended 3+ onsite auctions, hilling meetings
- Succeeded in 3 sales of collections (net value \$19.5M) and contributing to establishing TAMs category (AI art, NFTs)

# AI RESEARCH & FELLOWSHIPS

#### **Cambridge Machine Learning Fellow**

(1.5 week) Jan 2023

Cambridge AI Safety Hub's MLAB, Cambridge University | Cambridge, England

PI: Hannah Erlebach

- Gained technical experience with transformer interpretability, model training, and hyperparameter tuning
- Projects include building a raytracer, custom ResNet, simple backpropagation framework, custom BERT, and scaled GPT

#### **CSUN Machine Learning Student Assistant**

(7 mos) Nov 2021 – May 2022

AI-x Group, California State University: Northridge | Northridge, CA

PI: Prof. Wenchin Hsu

- Researched ML pedagogies and curriculum development for Prof Hsu's Spring 2023 graduate ML course
- Succeeded in delivering 280+ slides, 10+ Java-to-Python code conversion, and applying linear algebra to research

# **UF Bioinformatics Researcher**

(1 yr, 4 mos) Jun 2012 – Sep 2013

Systems Biology Laboratory, University of Florida | Gainesville, FL

PI: Prof. Su-Shing Chen

- Researched optimal parameter space for SVM techniques to detect influential biomarkers for Alzheimer's
- Co-authored research paper; published in Journal of Clinical Bioinformatics

## **SKILLS & FLUENCIES**

• Coding Languages: Python (OOP), C/C++, SQL (PostgreSQL), NoSQL (MongoDB), HTML/CSS/JS, APIs, Git

Machine Learning: SKLearn, Keras, TensorFlow, PyTorch, Numpy, Scipy

Cloud & DevOps: Google GCP, Google Collab, Hadoop/Spark, Docker, Github Pages, AWS

• Analytics/Visualization: Tableau, Google Sheets/Apps Script, Google Suite, Excel/VBA, Matplotlib, Seaborn

#### **HOBBIES**